

Sathya Narayanan Sudhakar

TECHNICAL LEAD + PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

Details

B+14 Phase 2, Parsn Palm Legend, Ondipudur Coimbatore, 641016 India 09952013313 sathya.remsit@gmail.com

Links

linkedIn/sathya-narayanan-sudhakar github/dizaina

Skills

Business Analysis

Design Thinking

Design Skills

Frontend Development

Backend Development

Knowledgable in User Interface/ User Experience

Customer Support

Strategic thinking

Digital Marketing

Market Research

Good people skills

Languages

English

Tamil

Profile

Technical leadership experience (10+ Years) centered at the intersection of marketing, design, engineering and dedicated to customer satisfaction with focused delivery of technical solution. Fast learner and highly adept in request for technology needs and team training.

Employment History

Technical lead + Product Management, AppViewX, Coimbatore

JULY 2015 - PRESENT

This project was about Automating and Orchestrating Certificates (CERT+) and Keys (KEY+) in the Cloud, Edge.

Technical Lead in CERT+ product

- Implemented MICROFRONTEND design approach in which web application is decomposed into individual, semi-independent "microapps" working loosely together.
- Modernized the web application from legacy code to REACT modules with lift and shift strategy.
- Optimized web performance with template engine (DustJS), minimalistic module loader (RequireJS), CSS & JS minification (Grunt).
- · Made the web compatible for SAAS model.
- Modern front end architecture (Core, Shared, Feature 1,2&3)
- Incorporated design system for the collection of repeatable components.
- Improved the overall performance by browser caching and reducing the DOM manipulation in the page rendering.
- Enabled Application Performance Index (APDEX) score in JMeter to measure user satisfaction.
- CI/CD for MICROFRONTEND build jobs using Jenkins.
- Technical lead role to oversee an engineering team and troubleshoot technical issues that involve engineering tasks and product releases.
- · Been open-minded and flexible in the workplace.

SSH+ Product Management

- Planned product road-map, organized the engineering team and managed the delivery.
- Created clickable prototypes, comprehensive layout and wire frames.
- · One-on-one interviews with customers.
- SSH+ as a product-led growth strategy.
- Product planning identifying and articulating market requirements for SSH+.
- Documents prepared are competitive analysis, PRD, road-maps, stories, release notes, user and admin guide.
- Market research, positioning, competitive analysis, market email campaign as a part of product marketing.
- · Wrote marketing blogs to increase the website traffic.

Initiatives

- Learn & Train: Hands-on training and learning for team members across organization in various technical stacks.
- KBytes: Email subscription platform to get latest front end updates.
- Design Thinking session for the product engineering team.
- Contextual Inquiry session with new joiners.

Internal awards

· Best Team and Most Valuable Player

Senior Software Engineer, Infosys, Chennai

JULY 2011 - JULY 2015

This Project was about developing and debugging the official website of a giant telecom company of the USA. The enhancements involved in were Mobile First Approach.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Developed responsive web design for both desktop and mobile devices using Twitter Bootstrap 3.0 and Angular JS 1.3 https://www.att.com/my/
- · Improved performance in Bootstrap and Angular JS.
- · Created an agile approach for the customer experience.
- · Led and trained team members and shared knowledge with customers.
- Investigated the root cause that are fixable across the technical stack in a project.
- · Quickly learned technical stacks across AT&T projects.
- · Been open-minded and flexible in the workplace.

Initiatives

- UI/UX revamp of AT&T-INFOSYS leave portal.
- AT&T Non disclosure agreement portal as smooth signature pad using HTML5 canvas.
- Implemented and automated centralized SVN to send emails for the team members.
- · Designed visual artifacts for INFOSYS internal communications.

Internal Awards

· Best Team and Most Valuable Player.

Education

BE, ECE, Dr Mahalingam College of Engineering and Technology, Coimbatore

APRIL 2008 - APRIL 2011

8.9 CGPA

Competency

Technical Skills

FULL STACK WEB development with Node JS, React JS, Firebase, MongoDB, Redux, Node JS, Webpack, GIT, Express JS, Web performance, jQuery, Dust JS

User-centricity

Usability experience with Contextual inquiry, Phone interview, Card sorting, Session recording, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Adobe after effects, Adobe XD. Invision studio

An experimentation mindset

Fail fast principle of freely experimenting and learning while trying to reach the desired result

Business Expert

Certificate and Keys life cycle management in Public Key Infrastructure